## Michael Paguay

michaelpaguay@me.com github.com/intrvertmichael linkedin.com/in/michaelpaguay Web Developer

Passionate developer with experience in Education and Graphic Design ready to develop tools that help improve the world.

Javascript, React, Redux, Sass, Node, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, Relational Database Design Storybook, Cypress, Jest, Figma, Adobe Suite: Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects

## **Projects**

Micro Reddit January 2021 Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Sass

- Recreated the original version of Reddit which allows users to post links, and vote/comment on posts. Ruby
  on Rails was used for the database, controllers, routing, and views.
- Built an adaptable SQL database, which, during deployment, was easily changed from SQLite to a PostgreSQL database. Used Active Record to create schemas, migrations, and relations.

<u>Memoir</u> November 2020 - December 2020 React, Redux, Sass, Storybook, Cypress

- Produced the front end of a reference application where users can create stories, and add entries. Modularly develop the application with global constants and testing.
- Worked remotely with a backend developer based in Toronto Canada. Completed the full scope of the application concurrently. We used Agile methodologies including daily scrums and sprint reviews.

Twitter Clone October 2020 - November 2020 React, Redux, Node, Express, MongoDB, JWT, BCrypt

- Recreated the original version of Twitter's core features: tweets, likes, hashtags, and comments. Used React
  and Redux to create the client-side user interface and experience.
- Established a secure user authentication system that does not allow foreign users to post with another user's account. Used Node Js to create web tokens and encrypt passwords.

### Education

- **DevOpen** Mentor Certification in Web Development 2020
- **CUNY Lehman College** Bachelor's of Science in Computer Graphics 2015
- Full Stack Open Deep Dive Into Modern Web Development
- The Odin Project Full Stack Ruby on Rails
- Free Code Camp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification
- **Udemy** Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp
- **Udemy** The Complete JavaScript Course
- Codingbat Java

# Experience

#### NYC Department of Education September 2012 - Current

Teaching Assistant

- Helped inner-city Emotionally Disturbed children with subjects including reading, writing, and math which
  resulted in students reaching their grade level expectations.
- Assisted students with conflict resolution techniques which improved learning and closer relationships with peers and educators.
- Used communication and adaptability to develop professional relationships with parents, teachers, supervisors, and therapists that helped students graduate into middle school and a few be able to integrate back into regular education.

#### Sign Guys NYC Architectural Signage January 2012 - October 2013

Graphic Designer

- Created signage alongside a team of graphic designers and fabricators which resulted in meeting all
  deadlines and optimizing the start to end process.
- Used creativity, time management skills, and communication to create vector art for customized building signage that followed the New York Graphic Signage Standards.

Soft Skills: Focused, Hard Working, Consistent, Responsive, Flexible